<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Ed Beach (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
	<Language_pt_BR>
		<!-- Entry UI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TITLE">
			<Text>American Civil War</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_DESC">
			<Text>From 1861 to 1865, America suffers through a bloody civil war with the brunt of the action centered between the capital cities of Washington and Richmond. Can you lead one of these fledgling nations to victory?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TURNS_REMAINING">
			<Text>Turns Left: {1_TurnsRemaining}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Dawn of Man-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]April the 12th, 1861. Confederate mortars open fire on Fort Sumter in Charleston harbor, signaling the start of America's Civil War. President Abraham Lincoln issues a call for volunteers for 90-day enlistments, confident that the rebellion can be put down in short order. Jefferson Davis, newly elected President of the Confederates States, is equally optimistic. Davis boldly moves his government to Richmond, Virginia, just 100 miles from Washington, D.C.  Can you win the swift victory both sides are predicting? Or will this war test if a nation conceived in liberty can long endure?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Win by capturing your opponent's capital before time runs out.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]City razing and settlers are off. Only cities with one of these production buildings may create units: either the {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BUILDING_ARSENAL} (Infantry), {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BUILDING_STABLE} (Cavalry), {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BUILDING_IRON_WORKS} (Artillery), or {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BUILDING_NAVY_YARD} (Naval Units). Capture enemy cities to control these production centers and the Manpower resource, necessary for Infantry units. All units of the player moving first receive just half their usual movement on the opening turn. Cities have no range strike and only minimal defense above the combat strength of any garrison. Great Generals' range increased to 5 and they are displaced to a nearby city rather than killed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Turns Remaining UI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BRIEFING_BUTTON">
			<Text>Briefing</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Victory-->
		<!-- Civilopedia-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_NAME">
			<Text>Abraham Lincoln</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>President of the United States of America</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_LIVED">
			<Text>1809 - 1865 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Born in 1809 in a small cabin in central Kentucky, Abraham Lincoln rose from seemingly humble beginnings to become one of the greatest statesmen in American history. In his early 20s, Lincoln served in a number of small government roles before his election to the Illinois General Assembly in 1834. In 1836 he began practicing law, and it wasn't long before he established a reputation as a savvy lawyer willing to take on a wide variety of cases. During successive terms in the Illinois House of Representatives and later a single term in the U.S. House of Representatives, Lincoln became known for his views opposing the further spread of slavery in the United States, a key issue that became a hallmark of his political career.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Election</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_TEXT_2">
			<Text>In 1860, Lincoln successfully campaigned to become the 16th President of the United States. It was during the now famous Lincoln-Douglas debates that the specter of southern secession was first raised, when Lincoln continually rebuked the notion of allowing slavery to spread into the western territories of the United States. The southern states, united in their continued support for slavery, were prepared to abandon the United States if Lincoln were to be elected.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Fort Sumter</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_TEXT_3">
			<Text>Soon after Lincoln's victory the first seven states to secede, led by South Carolina, and soon followed by Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas, declared their sovereignty and formed the Confederate States of America in 1861. In naming Jefferson Davis as their president-elect, the southern states made good on their threat to secede, and it wasn't long before one of America's most devastating conflicts, the Civil War, began with a confederate attack on Fort Sumter in April of 1861.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Emancipation Proclamation</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Lincoln assumed command of the Union war effort as commander-in-chief, issuing unprecedented orders to imprison confederate sympathizers, blockade all confederate ports, and to seize and free any slave used in the confederate war effort. His most aggressive and noteworthy order, the Emancipation Proclamation, was signed on January 1st, 1863, and provided freedom to all slaves within the confederacy, although it did not grant them full citizenship within the United States.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Gettysburg Address</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Months later, Lincoln gave what would become one of the most famous speeches in history, the Gettysburg Address. His renowned opening line - "Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent a new nation, conceived in liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal" - lives on today as one of the greatest reminders of Lincoln's mark on American history.  
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Judgement of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_GEORGE_TEXT_6">
			<Text>Following nearly five years of warfare, during which time over 500,000 Americans fought and died, the Civil War ended with the surrender of General Robert E. Lee in April of 1865. Just five days later, while attending a play at Ford's Theater in Washington D.C., Lincoln was assassinated by the Confederate sympathizer John Wilkes Booth. Although Lincoln did not survive to see the eventual outcome of his efforts to reestablish the nation and abolish slavery, the legacy of his deeds has long since established his position among America's greatest presidents.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV_UNITEDSTATES_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV_UNITEDSTATES_TEXT_1">
			<Text>During the American Civil War, the Union was the name used to reference the states still aligned with the federal government of the United States. Mainly comprised of states that had already outlawed slavery without a federal mandate, 20 in all, the North also controlled five slaveholding border states. The Union was led by President Abraham Lincoln, who oversaw both the logistical and tactical aspects of the war against the South.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]From the onset of the war, the Union states had vastly more resources and manpower available to fuel their efforts, with the North being much more industrialized than the South. The Union also had a much larger population from which to recruit soldiers, outnumbering the South nearly four to one. However, despite these advantages, the Union was still faced with a difficult task in reclaiming the southern states. The Confederate armies were led by skilled officers, and fighting to defend their home states gave the Confederates a distinct advantage in their knowledge of the terrain.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_NAME">
			<Text>Jefferson Davis</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Provisional President of the Confederacy</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_LIVED">
			<Text>1808 - 1889 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Jefferson Davis, born in 1808, was an American politician and military officer elected to lead the Confederate States of America following the secession of southern states in 1861. After attending the United States Military Academy in West Point and serving at Fort Crawford, Davis moved to Mississippi where he operated a plantation. After serving briefly in the Mexican-American war, Jefferson Davis returned to Mississippi and was appointed by the governor to serve in the U.S. Senate in 1848. As a slave owner and military veteran, Davis was seen as the embodiment of southern values, a sentiment that would help him in his burgeoning political career.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_2">
			<Text>Secession</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_2">
			<Text>In 1853, Davis was appointed Secretary of War under newly elected president Franklin Peirce. After serving his term, he returned to the Senate in 1857, where he urged restraint against secessionist movements brewing in the southern states. However, following Lincoln's victory in the presidential election of 1860, Mississippi joined six other states in seceding from the union, and Davis resigned his senate seat to return home. Although Davis had only anticipated serving the newly formed Confederate States of America in a military leadership role, he was selected by acclamation to serve as provisional President of the Confederacy in 1861.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_3">
			<Text>Fort Sumter</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_3">
			<Text>As the Confederate President, Davis attempted to negotiate for the acquisition of several Union-held forts that remained within the new Confederate territory. President Lincoln had no interest in ceding any territory to the South, and sent orders for Fort Sumter in South Carolina to be resupplied with food and materials. Viewing this as an act of war, the Confederate troops under General P.G.T. Beauregard bombarded the fort - marking the beginning of the American Civil War.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_4">
			<Text>Limited Resources</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_4">
			<Text>Jefferson Davis took it upon himself to directly oversee many of the strategies employed by the Southern armies. He was quick to recognize that the Confederacy had limited resources and equipment in comparison to the larger Union army, and sought to rely on a staunch defense rather than an aggressive offensive approach. However, after this strategy proved successful in protecting the Confederate capital in Richmond, Virginia, Davis and his senior advisor, General Robert E. Lee, pressed forward with plans for an invasion of the North.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_5">
			<Text>Invasion of the North</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_5">
			<Text>Despite General Lee's brilliance as a military tactician and leader, the Confederate campaign to invade the northern states was met with hard fighting at every turn. At the Battle of Antietam in September of 1862, the Confederates suffered over 10,000 casualties, and later still at the Battle of Gettysburg another 20,000 men or more were killed or wounded (an event widely considered the turning point of the war.)
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_6">
			<Text>Surrender</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_6">
			<Text>By 1865, the Confederacy was in dire shape, and by April of that year Union commander Ulysses S. Grant was nearly ready to seize the Confederate capital in Richmond. General Robert E. Lee and the Army of Northern Virginia surrendered just days later, and Jefferson Davis and his Cabinet fled south. On May 5, 1865, the Confederate government was officially dissolved in Washington, Georgia.
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_7">
			<Text>Capture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_7">
			<Text>On May 10th, Davis was captured by Union troops and held in confinement for just over two years. Eventually released on bail, Davis spent much of the next decade working quietly, avoiding much in the way of public appearances or discourse on the outcome of the war. 
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_HEADING_8">
			<Text>Judgement of History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_LEADERS_ELIZABETH_TEXT_8">
			<Text>Jefferson Davis passed away in 1889 at the age of 81, after suffering from an unknown illness that kept him bedridden for several months. Following his death, numerous memorials were constructed in his honor, and his legacy is still held in high regard among historians and the descendants of those who fought and died for the Confederacy. 
			</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV_ENGLAND_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV_ENGLAND_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Confederate States of America, also known as the Confederacy, was the name chosen by the southern states that opted to secede from the U.S. following Abraham Lincoln's election to the presidency in 1860. Viewing Lincoln's perspectives on slavery as leading to an infringement upon the individual rights of each state, including their right to break from the constitution and secede, the southern states did just that.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Confederate President, Jefferson Davis, sought to directly oversee not only the logistical issues of the war effort, but also the military strategies and appointments of the southern armies (much like his counterpart in the North). The Confederacy was faced with war against an opponent armed with superior equipment, greater manpower, and more raw materials dedicated to the conflict. These concerns did little to hamper the southern forces' enthusiasm for the fight ahead, as they viewed this as a battle for their way of life and the individual rights of every state versus the federal government.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_BLOCKADE_RUNNER_TEXT">
			<Text>The Confederate blockade runners were light, fast merchant ships commissioned to slip past or outrun Union warships that tried to enforce the Anaconda Plan, a strategy to deprive the South of its cotton trade with the European nations. Running cotton out and medical and military supplies in was a lucrative, if dangerous, business for Southern captains; by the end of the war, the Union had captured 1100 blockade runners and destroyed 355 more.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_CARBINE_CAVALRY_TEXT">
			<Text>Carbines, with a shorter barrel than a rifle, were less accurate but much easier to use when mounted. Most Union and a few Confederate cavalry regiments had been equipped with carbines by war's end, which proved their worth in cavalry actions such as Brandy Station and Yellow Tavern.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_INFANTRY_CORPS_TEXT">
			<Text>On both sides the infantry corps was the major organizational formation of the armies; in the Confederate Army these would comprise two to four divisions and be named for its commander (e.g. Longstreet's Corps), whereas Union Corps were standardized at three divisions and simply numbered. A corps would comprise between 10,000 and 25,000 men, commanded by a lieutenant general on the Southern side and a major general in the Northern armies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_INFANTRY_DIVISION_TEXT">
			<Text>An infantry division was generally made up of two to four brigades, each brigade between 1200 and 2500 soldiers. Commanded by a general, the division was the basic unit of maneuver during battle; in theory, these generals were tasked with husbanding the striking power of their division until able to deliver one hard blow rather than a series of lesser ones.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_RIFLED_CANNON_TEXT">
			<Text>Rifling adds grooves to the inside of the barrel of cannon to improve the range and accuracy of the piece, at the cost of increased expense to manufacture and the need for a longer barrel. Although various makes of rifled artillery were supplied to the Civil War armies, the most famous is the Parrott Rifle, used by both sides in different sizes, from the common 10-pounders for field use up to the emplaced 300-pounders in fortifications.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_MILITARY_ENGINEER_TEXT">
			<Text>Military engineering is loosely defined as the art of designing and building military fortifications and maintaining the lines of military transport and communications. In the Civil War, with recent advances in technology, military engineers were not only responsible for field and permanent fortifications, bridges and bases, but tasked with constructing and repairing the rail and telegraph lines that so dramatically changed the nature of warfare.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_IRONCLAD_TEXT">
			<Text>The first steam-driven warship plated with iron or steel was launched by the French Navy in 1859, but the first battles involving ironclads took place in 1862 during the Civil War. It quickly became clear that the ironclad had replaced the wooden ship-of-the-line as the most powerful warship afloat; by the end of the war the Confederate Navy launched 24 ironclads (although 59 were begun, several being destroyed before completion), while the Union commissioned 52 coastal ironclads.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_MONITOR_TEXT">
			<Text>In the Civil War, a "monitor" was an armored, steam-driven warship with a very low freeboard (as a foot from waterline to deck) mounting a few heavy guns in one or more turrets. Intended primarily for use on the rivers that cut through Southern territory, the unseaworthy craft were used to support land forces, protect riverbank positions, and control river passage; monitors were crucial to the Union victories in the West, notably along the Mississippi River.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_RESOURCE_MANPOWER_TEXT">
			<Text>The United States first used conscription to raise manpower for the military during the Civil War, passing an act authorizing the draft of citizens to supplement the volunteers. The Confederate States president Jefferson Davis proposed the first Southern conscription act in March 1862 as volunteer furloughs loomed; it was passed by the Confederate Congress the next month. The conscription laws of both nations sought to answer the manpower deficiencies brought about by the high casualty rates, but proved increasingly unpopular as the war progressed.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_RESOURCE_MANPOWER_HELP">
			<Text>Manpower is produced by Barracks, and is required to maintain your Infantry. Protecting your Manpower-producing Barracks is critical to victory, especially in the South, where Manpower is in short supply.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Civ Traits-->
		<!-- Scenario-specific Diplomacy Modifiers-->
		<!-- Technologies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_RIFLED_ARTILLERY_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Rifled Cannon[ENDCOLOR], an artillery unit with Range of 3.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_RIFLED_ARTILLERY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The Yankee three-inch rifle was a dead shot at any distance under a mile. They could hit the end of a flour barrel more often than miss, unless the gunner got rattled."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Confederate gunner at the Battle of Atlanta[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_RIFLED_ARTILLERY_DESC">
			<Text>Rifling adds grooves to the inside of the barrel of cannon to improve the range and accuracy of the piece, at the cost of increased expense to manufacture and the need for a longer barrel. Both the Union and Confederate armies in the Eastern Theater included batteries of rifled artillery, along with batteries of mixed smooth-bore and rifled cannons.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Infantry Corps[ENDCOLOR], an upgrade to the Infantry Division that requires more manpower but has a much higher [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Why do they call them civil wars when they always are so extraordinarily uncivil?"[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Elizabeth Fitch[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_SCIENCE_DESC">
			<Text>At the beginning of the Civil War there were several military academies devoted to educating young men in military science, most notably the U.S. Military Academy at West Point. The South, on the other hand, boasted more, and arguably better, private academies catering to the Southern traditions: the Citadel, Virginia Military Academy, Porter Military Academy in South Carolina, St. Charles College in Mississippi and others.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENGINEERING_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT][TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_WORKER[1]][ENDCOLOR], a civilian unit that can repair improvements, build Roads and Railroads. This unit can also be consumed to construct a Citadel or Pontoon Bridge.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENGINEERING_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Quit thinking about what Bobby Lee's gonna do to us and start thinking about what we're going to do to him."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ulysses S. Grant[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENGINEERING_DESC">
			<Text>Although the Union engineers were blessed with plentiful materials and labor and Southern engineers with imagination and necessity, both were challenged by the changing technology of mass warfare: telegraphy, railroads, barbed wire, pontoon bridges, balloons, and the like.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_REPEATING_RIFLES_HELP">
			<Text>Permite treinar a [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Cavalaria com Carabina[ENDCOLOR], uma evolução da Divisão de Cavalaria com o dobro da [ICON_STRENGTH]Força de Combate.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_REPEATING_RIFLES_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Our best officers estimate one man armed with a Spencer Carbine is equivalent to three with any other arm."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Major-General James H. Wilson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_REPEATING_RIFLES_DESC">
			<Text>A Guerra Civil é mencionada frequentemente como a primeira guerra "moderna" da história, devido em parte ao uso de armas inovadoras; uma das mais decisivas no nível tático foram os {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_REPEATING_RIFLES_TITLE}, uma arma de cano único que levava múltiplos cartuchos de munição, em que a ação de recarga do rifle também reengatilha o mecanismo de disparo.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_IRONCLADS_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Ironclads[ENDCOLOR], a powerful naval unit that will dominate wooden naval vessels.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_IRONCLADS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The turrets and other parts of the ship were heavily struck, but the shots did not penetrate; the tower was intact, and it continued to revolve. A look of confidence passed over the men's faces, and we believed the Merrimac would not repeat the work she had accomplished the day before."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Samuel Dana Greene[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_IRONCLADS_DESC">
			<Text>In an attempt to break the Union blockade, the Confederacy was the first in the Civil War to turn to constructing an ironclad; in October 1861 the CSS Manassas became the first ironclad to enter combat, engaging Union warships in the Battle of the Head of Passes - a battle overshadowed by the first ironclad clash between the CSS Merrimack and the USS Monitor the following February.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_CAVALRY_RAIDS_HELP">
			<Text>Allows cavalry units to pillage enemy tiles. Prior to researching this tech, no unit can pillage enemy territory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_CAVALRY_RAIDS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Jeb Stuart is my ideal of a cavalry leader, prompt, vigilant, and fearless."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Thomas J. Jackson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_CAVALRY_RAIDS_DESC">
			<Text>The Confederacy, fighting a defensive war, was the first to initiate large-scale cavalry raids, numbering from a few hundred to two thousand mounted troops, sweeping behind the lines to disrupt the enemy forces and dismay the enemy civilian population. Confederate cavalry generals such as J.E.B. Stuart, John Hunt Morgan and "Jo" Shelby became infamous for their deep raids, burning bridges, warehouses and towns and scattering livestock and destroying crops.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_FIELD_HOSPITALS_HELP">
			<Text>Doubles the healing rate of all your units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_FIELD_HOSPITALS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"This conflict is one thing I've been waiting for. I'm well and strong and young - young enough to go to the front. If I can't be a soldier, I'll help soldiers."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Clara Barton[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_FIELD_HOSPITALS_DESC">
			<Text>Before the Civil War, armies tended to be small, mostly due to logistic and mobilization issues. But the larger, more rapidly moving armies and the increasing lethality of the weaponry brought a demand by civilians and officers alike for a better method of treating the wounded. On the Union side, following the Battle of Bull Run General McClellan appointed surgeon Charles Tipler the first medical director for the Army of the Potomac; in 1862 William Hammond was named Surgeon general of the United States and launched a number of reforms in the evacuation, treatment and recovery procedures for the wounded, including integrated field hospitals operating right at the front lines.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_BALLOON_RECONNAISSANCE_HELP">
			<Text>Gives all Generals extra visibility.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_BALLOON_RECONNAISSANCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I have pleasure in sending you this first dispatch ever telegraphed from an aerial station."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Thaddeus S. C. Lowe[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_BALLOON_RECONNAISSANCE_DESC">
			<Text>With the outbreak of war, the United States War Department would create a balloon corps; the civilian Thaddeus Lowe would be named the corps first commander with the lofty title "Chief Aeronaut." Union general McDowell first called on the corps to provide aerial observations of enemy encampments and movements during the First Battle of Bull Run.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_RAILROADS_HELP">
			<Text>Halves the time to construct Railroads and doubles your movement rate on Railroads.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_RAILROADS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The North can make a steam engine, locomotive or railway car; hardly a yard of cloth or a pair of shoes can you make. You are rushing into war with one of the most powerful, ingeniously mechanical and determined people on earth-right at your doors."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - William Tecumseh Sherman[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_MILITARY_RAILROADS_DESC">
			<Text>The United States Military Railroad was established by the U.S. War Department in 1862 to operate any rail lines seized by the federal government after Congress authorized Lincoln to commandeer railroads and telegraph lines for use by the military. By war's end, the USMRR controlled over 2000 miles of Northern track and captured Southern rail lines.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_INDUSTRIALIZATION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Gatling Guns[ENDCOLOR], a powerful unit with Range of 1.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_INDUSTRIALIZATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"This year's brought about many changes that at the beginning would've been thought impossible."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Christian Fleetwood[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_INDUSTRIALIZATION_DESC">
			<Text>Already industrialized, the Union spent the war refining and perfecting methods of mass production and transport of weapons, clothing, and military supplies of all types in large quantities. The Southern states, by contrast were largely agrarian at the start of the war, importing most manufactured goods from the North or Europe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_SCORCHED_EARTH_HELP">
			<Text>Allows infantry units to pillage enemy tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_SCORCHED_EARTH_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"War is hell."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - William Tecumseh Sherman[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_SCORCHED_EARTH_DESC">
			<Text>An ancient strategy, "scorched earth" refers to campaigns aimed at destroying everything that might be useful to the enemy, including civilian property. In the Civil War, faced with a war that had lasted long enough to prove increasingly unpopular on the home front, the United States initiated the policy, most famously during Sherman's march to the sea and Sheridan's campaign in the Shenandoah Valley.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENTRENCHMENT_HELP">
			<Text>Doubles the combat bonus for being fortified.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENTRENCHMENT_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I have always regretted that the last assault at Cold Harbor was ever made."[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB] - Ulysses S. Grant[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_TECH_ENTRENCHMENT_DESC">
			<Text>A field fortification meant to protect infantry from cavalry and missile fire, entrenchments have been used in warfare since the earliest days; during the Civil War, temporary entrenchments were dug during battles, as at Gettysburg, while more elaborate, extensive entrenchments protected strategic cities such as Washington and Richmond.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_SCENARIO_TECH_BUTTON_1">
			<Text>Allows cavalry to pillage tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_SCENARIO_TECH_BUTTON_2">
			<Text>Allows infantry to pillage tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Resources -->
		<!-- Improvements-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PONTOON_BRIDGE">
			<Text>Pontoon Bridge</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PONTOON_BRIDGE_HELP">
			<Text>Allows land units to traverse this Coast tile. May only be constructed in a Coast tile with 4 or more land tiles adjacent to it. Constructed by an embarked {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_WORKER[1]}, who is consumed by the construction of the Pontoon Bridge.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PONTOON_BRIDGE_TEXT">
			<Text>Pontoon (or "floating") bridges were used by both sides during the war to allow the rapid crossing of rivers by infantry, artillery and wagons; an innovative, light-weight design known as Cumberland Pontoons was especially crucial during the Union campaigns across the deep South.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_PONTOON_BRIDGE">
			<Text>Construct a [LINK=IMPROVEMENT_PONTOON_BRIDGE]Pontoon Bridge[\LINK]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_PONTOON_BRIDGE_HELP">
			<Text>Allows land units to traverse this Coast tile. May only be constructed in a Coast tile with 4 or more land tiles adjacent to it. Constructed by an embarked {TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_WORKER[1]}, who is consumed by the construction of the Pontoon Bridge.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILD_PONTOON_BRIDGE_REC">
			<Text>It will allow land units to traverse this hex.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BUILD_RAILROAD_HELP">
			<Text>An unbroken chain of Railroads allows Units to move extremely quickly through Tiles.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Connecting Cities to your capital by Railroad will give them a 25% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production bonus.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BUILD_ROAD_HELP">
			<Text>An unbroken chain of Roads allows Units to move more quickly across the map.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Connecting Cities to your capital will provide a large amount of [ICON_GOLD] Gold per turn.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Buildings in the seperate Buildings file-->
		<!-- Units-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_WORKER">
			<Text>A civilian unit that can repair improvements, build Roads and Railroads. This unit can also be consumed to construct a Citadel or Pontoon Bridge.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--Great Generals-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_IRVIN_MCDOWELL">
			<Text>Irvin McDowell</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARO_GEORGE_MCCLELLAN">
			<Text>George McClellan</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_AMBROSE_BURNSIDE">
			<Text>Ambrose Burnside</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_JOE_HOOKER">
			<Text>Joe Hooker</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_GEORGE_MEADE">
			<Text>George Meade</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_ULYSSES_GRANT">
			<Text>Ulysses Grant</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_JOE_JOHNSTON">
			<Text>Joe Johnston</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_ROBERT_E_LEE">
			<Text>Robert E. Lee</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Promotions-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_MORALE">
			<Text>Rebel Yell</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_MORALE_HELP">
			<Text>+10% [ICON_STRENGTH] Combat Strength.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_BALLOON_RECON">
			<Text>Balloon Reconnaissance</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_BALLOON_RECON_HELP">
			<Text>+2 Visibility Range for Great Generals.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_IGNORES_GREAT_GENERAL">
			<Text>Ignores Great Generals</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_IGNORES_GREAT_GENERAL_HELP">
			<Text>Does not receive bonuses from nearby Great Generals.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!--In-Game Messages-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BLOCKADE_RUNNER_YOURS">
			<Text>Your {1_UnitName} has slipped by the Northern blockade, arrived in Europe, and sold its cargo of cotton for [ICON_GOLD] {2_GoldAmount}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_BLOCKADE_RUNNER_THEIRS">
			<Text>A Confederate {1_UnitName} sneaked by the coastal securities and is destined for Europe. Its cargo of cotton will bring [ICON_GOLD] {2_GoldAmount} to the Confederacy.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_JOHN_ERICSSON">
			<Text>PRO-UNION EVENT: John Ericsson[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Swedish-born inventor John Ericsson has joined the Union cause. Perhaps this Grande Cientista can aid the Union in developing new technology such as the Monitor ironclad?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_EMANCIPATION">
			<Text>PRO-UNION EVENT: Emancipation Proclamation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Abraham Lincoln has issued a great proclamation declaring freedom for all those persons enslaved in Confederate territory.  Union Manpower is raised by {1_Num}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_CLARA_BARTON">
			<Text>PRO-UNION EVENT: Clara Barton[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The humanitarian Clara Barton has been appointed to head up the Union field hospitals in this theater. Because of the efforts of this "Angel of the Battlefield", Union Manpower is raised by {1_Num}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_CALL_VOLUNTEERS">
			<Text>PRO-UNION EVENT: Call for Volunteers[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Abraham Lincoln's urgent appeal for Union volunteers has been answered. {1_Num} divisions of Union infantry have just arrived via rail from the Northeast.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_WESTERN_CRISIS">
			<Text>PRO-UNION EVENT: Western Crisis[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Union victory at Vicksburg has left the Confederate forces in the West in disarray. Reinforcements will need to be sent to Mississippi. Confederate Manpower is dropped by {1_Num}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_CSA_INFLATION">
			<Text>PRO-UNION EVENT: Confederate Inflation[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The Confederate currency has been devalued!  The [ICON_GOLD] Gold in the Confederate treasury has dropped by {1_Num}%.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_GEORGE_RAINS">
			<Text>PRO-CONFEDERATE EVENT: George W. Rains[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]George Washington Rains and his brother Gabriel have been experimenting with explosive devices. Perhaps this Grande Cientista can aid the Confederate in developing new technology such as improved artillery?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_WESTERN_RAIL">
			<Text>PRO-CONFEDERATE EVENT: Western Reinforcements[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]{1_Num} divisions of Confederate infantry have just arrived via rail from the Western Theater. Surely these troops are needed more urgently here in the East!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_NYC_DRAFT_RIOTS">
			<Text>PRO-CONFEDERATE EVENT: New York City Draft Riots[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Civil unrest has overtaken New York City! Rioting has broken out over the Union's latest draft laws conscripting men for military service.  Troops will need to be diverted to quell the unrest. Union Manpower is dropped by {1_Num}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_COTTON_PRICES">
			<Text>PRO-CONFEDERATE EVENT: Cotton Prices[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Cotton prices soar in Europe. Confederate profits from blockade running increase dramatically. The Confederate cause gains {1_Num} [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_MOSBYS_RAIDERS">
			<Text>PRO-CONFEDERATE EVENT: Mosby's Raiders[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Confederate partisan raiders led by John S. Mosby have captured several major Union wagon trains in Northern Virginia. {1_Num}% of the current Union [ICON_GOLD] Gold in their treasury has been taken by the Confederates!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_LEE_ARRIVES">
			<Text>PRO-CONFEDERATE EVENT: Robert E. Lee Takes Command[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Joe Johnston has been injured in battle. Robert E. Lee is promoted to command of the Army of Northern Virginia. This raises the Confederate Great General combat modifier from +20% to +30%.  All units starting the turn within 5 hexes gain +1 [ICON_MOVES] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_MCCLELLAN">
			<Text>NEW UNION COMMANDER: George McClellan[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the defeat at {1_CityName}, Lincoln feels it is time to replace the current Union commander. George McClellan is put in command. He provides only a 10% combat modifier. However McClellan is a master at training new troops. When present in a city that constructs a new infantry unit, a SECOND unit is instantly created at the same time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_HOOKER">
			<Text>NEW UNION COMMANDER: Ambrose Burnside[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the defeat at {1_CityName}, Lincoln feels it is time to replace the current Union commander. Ambrose Burnside is put in command. He provides only a 10% combat modifier. However Burnside is determined to get the Army of Potomac on the move. All units starting the turn within 5 hexes gain +1 [ICON_MOVES] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_BURNSIDE">
			<Text>NEW UNION COMMANDER: Joe Hooker[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the defeat at {1_CityName}, Lincoln feels it is time to replace the current Union commander. Joe Hooker is put in command. He provides a 20% combat modifier.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_MEADE">
			<Text>NEW UNION COMMANDER: George Meade[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]After the defeat at {1_CityName}, Lincoln once again looks for a new commander. George Meade is put in command, a clear upgrade over the previous leadership. He provides a significant combat modifier of +30%. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EVENT_GRANT">
			<Text>NEW UNION COMMANDER: Ulysses Grant[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Lincoln has at last found his man. Ulysses Grant, already victorious in numerous Western Theater campaigns, is brought east and put in command. He provides a 30% combat modifier and all units starting the turn within 5 hexes gain +1 [ICON_MOVES] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_CIV5_IMPROVEMENTS_CITADEL_TEXT">
			<Text>A Citadel is a mighty fortification that can only be constructed by an Engineer. Upon constructing the Citadel, your Culture borders will also expand to surround the Citadel on all sides by one hex. Any unit stationed within a Citadel receives a 100% defensive strength bonus. Additionally, any enemy unit which ends its turn next to a Citadel takes 30 damage (damage does not stack with other Citadels).</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIVIL_WAR_SCENARIO_EO_EX_IMPROVEMENTS">
			<Text>Total cost of maintaining Roads and Railroads you have built, or are responsible for.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_pt_BR>
</GameData>
