<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- edited with XMLSPY v2004 rel. 2 U (http://www.xmlspy.com) by Anton Strenger (Firaxis Games) -->
<GameData>
	<Language_pt_BR>
		<!-- Entry UI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TITLE">
			<Text>Empires of the Smoky Skies</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_DESC">
			<Text>The advent of steam power has revolutionized the world.  It is a time of discovery, fueled by newfound resources and brilliant inventions. Can you harness the power of steam to bring your people to greatness?</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_RANDOM_MAP">
			<Text>Random Map</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_FIXED_MAP">
			<Text>Fixed Map</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Notifications-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_NOTIF_SUMMARY">
			<Text>{@1_CivName} becomes {@2_TitleName}!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_NOTIF_TT">
			<Text>{@1_CivName} has gained the Honourable Title of [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]{@2_TitleName}[ENDCOLOR], giving them more control in the League of Empires and bringing them closer to victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Turns Remaining UI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TURNS_REMAINING">
			<Text>{1_TokensOwned} of {2_TokensAvailable} Titles</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_BRIEFING_BUTTON">
			<Text>Briefing</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VSCREEN_BUTTON">
			<Text>League of Empires</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Victory Status UI-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_HELP">
			<Text>The League of Empires convenes annually to determine the most worthy world leaders and confer Honourable Titles upon them.  The first leader to hold {1_NumTokensNeededForVictory} or more Titles for {2_NumTurnsNeededForVictory} Turns will control the League and win the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_POSSIBLE">
			<Text>As of Year {1_YearUpdated : number #}:</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_LOCKED">
			<Text>Victory is not yet possible.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_COUNTDOWN">
			<Text>{1_NumTurnsUntilVictory} Turns until {@2_CivAboutToWin} wins!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_TURN_UNLOCK">
			<Text>Available on Turn {1_UnlockTurn}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_TECH_UNLOCK">
			<Text>Available once any player researches {1_Technology:textkey}.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_VALUE_UNLOCK">
			<Text>Available once any player gets to {1_UnlockValue} in this field.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_UNLOCK_TT">
			<Text>The Title of [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]{@1_TitleName}[ENDCOLOR] becomes available for all players.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_MILITARY">
			<Text>Military</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_MILITARY_TITLE">
			<Text>Defender of Progress</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_MILITARY_HELP">
			<Text>Number of Latest Landships and Airships</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_MILITARY_TT">
			<Text>Once someone builds a more advanced model, older models are outdated and no longer count.  These older models, though, can still be upgraded to be competitive.  If someone else is in the lead you can build new units, upgrade old ones, or attack their army to shrink its size.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Latest landship type: {@1_LandshipUnitType}[NEWLINE]Latest airship type: {@2_AirshipUnitType}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_CULTURE">
			<Text>Culture</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_CULTURE_TITLE">
			<Text>Lord of Refinement</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_CULTURE_HELP">
			<Text>Social Policies Adopted</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_CULTURE_TT">
			<Text>Adopt more social policies than your rivals.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_INDUSTRY">
			<Text>Industry</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_INDUSTRY_TITLE">
			<Text>Captain of Industry</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_INDUSTRY_HELP">
			<Text>Highest Production City</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_INDUSTRY_TT">
			<Text>The cities with the highest [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production in each individual empire are compared, and the Title given to the most productive city's owner.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]World's most productive city: {@1_WorldBestCity}[NEWLINE]Your most productive city: {@2_YourBestCity}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_COMMERCE">
			<Text>Commerce</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_COMMERCE_TITLE">
			<Text>Master of Wealth</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_COMMERCE_HELP">
			<Text>Total Gross Gold Income</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_COMMERCE_TT">
			<Text>The gross amount of gold acquired throughout the game.  Only the raw gold income is examined, so maintenance and other expenses do not subtract from this score.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_LABOR">
			<Text>Labor</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_LABOR_TITLE">
			<Text>Grand Philanthropist</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_LABOR_HELP">
			<Text>World Wonders and National Wonders</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_LABOR_TT">
			<Text>Each World Wonder and National Wonder you control counts equally towards your score.  If your rivals construct World Wonders first you can build National Wonders to catch up, or attack their cities and claim their Wonders as your own.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_CATEGORY_HELP_TT">
			<Text>In the event of a tie, no player receives the Title.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Dawn of Man-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT">
			<Text>SCENARIO DESCRIPTION[NEWLINE]Greetings to you, renowned Captain of science and industry!  The advent of steam power has revolutionized the world.  It is a time of discovery, fueled by newfound resources and brilliant inventions.  Great airships trek across the skies, marking their trails with black smoke.  Civilizations are propelled towards a bright future, but competition is fierce.  Resources are scarce, and technological secrets are carefully guarded.  You and your rivals must expand your empires across the globe to meet growing needs in the name of progress.  Can you harness the power of steam technology and bring your people to greatness?[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]VICTORY CONDITIONS[NEWLINE]Empires compete in the domains of Military, Culture, Industry, Commerce, and Labor.  Be the best in a domain to earn an Honourable Title.  To see the specifics of each Title, and monitor your progress, check the League of Empires screen.  The first empire to hold three or more Titles wins the game.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]SPECIAL RULES[NEWLINE]Players begin with all technologies up through Steam Power.  The tech tree after Steam Power has been altered significantly, giving players the ability to construct Airships, Landships, and new buildings.  Barbarians ("Luddites") are enabled, but do not have access to advanced units.  Social Policies have been rearranged.  Religion has been disabled, as have religious and militaristic city-states.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- <Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_GERMANY_TEXT">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_RUSSIA_TEXT">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_ENGLAND_TEXT">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_SWEDEN_TEXT">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_FRANCE_TEXT">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV5_DAWN_TEXT}</Text>
		</Row>-->
		<!-- Victory-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_TIME">
			<Text>Empire</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_TIME_BANG">
			<Text>Empire Victory!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_VICTORY_FLAVOR_TIME">
			<Text>The League of Empires bows before you.  You have proven that your civilization is the most worthy, and will guide humanity's ascent into the future.   The skies are yours.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Civs and Leaders-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ROFFENBURG_NAME">
			<Text>Cyrus Rotheram</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CURNOW_NAME">
			<Text>Ignace Curnow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CUTLER_NAME">
			<Text>Octavius Cutler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GRIGGS_NAME">
			<Text>Luther Griggs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ALDERDICE_NAME">
			<Text>Clinton Alderdice</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Scenario-specific Diplomacy Modifiers-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_SPECIFIC_DIPLO_STRING_1">
			<Text>You have 2 Titles, and pose a threat to them in the League.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_SPECIFIC_DIPLO_STRING_2">
			<Text>You have more than 2 Titles, and nearly control the League!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_SPECIFIC_DIPLO_STRING_3">
			<Text>You are competing over the same Titles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- historic entries -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_GERMANY_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_GERMANY_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The Eruch Empire began as a series of impassioned debates between long established noble families about the growing chaos in the world and what could be done to stop it.  The debates soon reached a critical mass for action, fueled by the nobles' fear of an uncertain future as well as their desire to protect their wealth.  A secret council was formed, drawing on the leadership and military prowess that had been their inheritance from previous generations.  It mobilized a small but well-equipped army.  With it, the nobles carved out a large territory that would become the core of Eruch, and seceded from the old kingdoms.  Outwardly, leaders of Eruch profess the glories of civilized life, and seek to spread their ways to the ends of the earth.  They act as gentlemen in diplomatic affairs, but always have a rigid structure of military might ready to respond at their first call.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_ENGLAND_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_ENGLAND_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The exact origins of Pulias are shrouded in mystery even to this day.  It seems to have emerged out of nowhere, yet its power and wealth seem too large to have been easily missed.  Most sources posit a single leader who saw the opportunities of new science, commerce, and most of all politics, and manipulated affairs from the shadows.  This leader sold sensitive information to rivals at a premium while using it to further the objectives of Pulias.  In the early competition between empires, many opportunities were left unexplored as rivals focused on short-term gains.  Pulias was the first to send expeditions to foreign lands, and established trade that brought riches to its citizens.  Its spies were placed in key positions across the world, gathering intelligence and ready to act.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_FRANCE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>Dalmace arose out of necessity.  The turmoil of old kingdoms collapsing and new empires emerging left many people of the lower and middle classes marginalized.  Some stayed in their homelands but many fled as refugees, not knowing where to go.  They gathered in the country estates of nobles that did not have the heart or the force to deny their presence.  Soon leaders arose from the ranks of the refugees, calling for organization, protection, food, and resources.  Some nobles saw opportunity and joined their ranks, sharing their wealth.  Others refused, and their estates were ransacked.  These were the first Dalmace compounds, which would grow into cities that rivaled those of any other empire.  Dalmace is founded on ideals, and its strength comes from the tight camaraderie and evolving culture of its humble citizens.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_RUSSIA_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_RUSSIA_TEXT_1">
			<Text>The steady advance of science brought great changes to the processes by which products were manufactured, transported, and sold.  Many otherwise shrewd businessmen could not contend with the changes and faded away, leaving room for the more adaptable.  Orlin had no political existence when it began, and no desire for empire.  It was a collection of ambitious industrialists that banded together for mutual benefit.  They parcelled out markets like territories, and together came to dominate industries throughout the old kingdoms.  When the kingdoms began to fade, the Orlin tycoons clashed in a contest for power.  They encroached on each other's ventures, and delved into blackmail and assassination.  A tight oligarchy emerged which controlled nearly all the means of production.  With their industrial capacity, and the riches it brought, they formally entered the world stage as an empire.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_SWEDEN_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_CIV_SWEDEN_TEXT_1">
			<Text>When the old kingdoms weakened, the growing class of academics and inventors saw the opportunity to create a new kind of nation, one that was founded on principles of reason and embraced scientific advancement.  They found allies in many of the old monarchists, who were looking for a way to preserve their influence, and together they became Vedria.  Their ranks mixed quickly, and before long every prominent leader was expected to be familiar with scientific processes, if not involved in research personally.  Vedria is marked by optimism for the future to come, and its citizens believe that the noble pursuit of science is the clear path towards it.  Scientists are consulted on matters of state, and given generous funding for their research.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_NAME">
			<Text>Cyrus Rotheram</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Eruch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_LIVED">
			<Text>1815 - 1872 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TEXT_1">
			<Text>"The military sciences are as complex as ever, yet we have more tools at our disposal than ever before.  Not a century ago, quelling the forces of a distant enemy required extensive fortifications, supply routes, and resources.  Horses had to be fed and quartered, and the loss of a supply line could mean the end of an otherwise honorable campaign.  Soldiers had to learn how to stare their enemy in the eye as they calmly readied their weapons and took life.  In our present age, soldiers can face each other in honorable combat while avoiding the savageries of the previous century.  The recent development of the Landship has made foot soldiers and cavalry all but obsolete.  Limited only by the resources needed to build it, the Landship can traverse a nation in a matter of days without need of rest.  Distant territories, once costly to conquer, are now within reach.  And with its cannons and near impenetrable armor, the Landship can easily make pliant all but the most savagely persistent of the uncivilized nations."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] - Cyrus Rotheram, address to the Eruch Senate
</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_NAME">
			<Text>Ignace Curnow</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Orlin</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_LIVED">
			<Text>1781 - 1836 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TEXT_1">
			<Text>"With the press of a button the steam jet enters the rig and begins the fabrication.  Gears turning in the rig, pressing hot steel, shaping it into newly minted gears.  A factory for making a factory.  Maybe we will use it to make even more products; or maybe we will sell it to someone else for a wide profit.  In this simple process is the proof of industry's role in our age.  We can make airships, landships, difference engines, clothing, and even factories.  By controlling the efficiency and maximizing the output of our industrial sector, we can make whatever we want, and be the best at it."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] - Ignace Curnow, excerpt from "Steel and Steam: An Industrialist's Guide"
</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_NAME">
			<Text>Octavius Cutler</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Pulias</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_LIVED">
			<Text>1809 - 1888 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TEXT_1">
			<Text>"There are those who say that power comes from science, and research is the way to more of it.  Others find power in inventing new military contraptions, rolling around with their Landships and locking away stores of resources.  But the true power is in none of these things.  It is in the people that make these things.  If we know what they know, then we have what they have.  Let them fight amongst themselves and strive towards new discoveries. We make it our business to match their every step from the shadows, and our collected power becomes greater than all of theirs.  If we do it right - and we must - they won't even notice."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] - Octavius Cutler, personal correspondence with newly appointed Intelligence Director
</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_NAME">
			<Text>Luther Griggs</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Vedria</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_LIVED">
			<Text>1842 - 1910 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TEXT_1">
			<Text>"Technological progress has brought marvels of mechanical achievement into our everyday life and allowed us to live in class and comfort.  The whirring of the difference engines, the clack of brass gears, the steady burst of steam exhaust like the breath of a bull about to charge; these bring order into our world and allow us to perform marvels of science and computation that not only explain the natural world, but bring our order to bear firmly upon its sturdy shoulders.  Airships have lifted our leaden bodies, once eternally bound to the earth, for sorties in the skies.  With the sharp force of mind we have made real the eternal human dream of flight.  And not with wings that the whims of natural selection deemed to give us, but with wings wrought from the sweat of our own brow and the fire of our own forge."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] - Luther Griggs, excerpt from "The Wings of Intellect"
</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_NAME">
			<Text>Clinton Alderdice</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_SUBTITLE">
			<Text>Leader of Dalmace</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_LIVED">
			<Text>1799 - 1855 AD</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_HEADING_1">
			<Text>History</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TEXT_1">
			<Text>"Of this above all do I pray you remember, Mr. Secretary.  The Age of Steam has improved the livelihood of our great powers, but it has done so at the cost of the common man.  The swath of achievements in the past decades has only made more clear what has been the black mark on human history: the powerful few exploit the powerless many.  We have dismissed their difficulties as petty squabble, and appealed to our gentlemanly demeanor and productive enterprises as justification for our power, but the reality is that conditions are improving for us while they get worse for the common man.  Left unchecked, this gap will continue to grow until the common man is no more than a serf.  If I cannot appeal to you and the League on moral grounds - as it so seems, for I have tried tirelessly - let me warn you that our great society is becoming more and more unstable.  The common man may not be as educated or refined as we, but he has eyes and ears and a mind, and he will not be able to ignore the decadence of our lifestyle.  He will compare it to his own, and he will conspire with his neighbor.  Together they will grow and form a disgruntled block, and before the century is out we will have an uncontrollable rebellion on our hands.  And no amount of difference engine calculations or airship bombardments will be able to stop it, because those are built on the labor of those who have turned against us."[NEWLINE][NEWLINE] - Clinton Alderdice, letter to the Grand Secretary of the League of Empires
</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Traits-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_FRONTIER_MARKETS_SHORT">
			<Text>Frontier Markets</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_FRONTIER_MARKETS">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold from strategic resources, and [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium resources provide double quantity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_OPTIMIZED_EXTRACTORS_SHORT">
			<Text>Optimized Extractors</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_OPTIMIZED_EXTRACTORS">
			<Text>+1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production from strategic resources, and [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric resources provide double quantity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_NEW_WORLD_ORDER_SHORT">
			<Text>New World Order</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_NEW_WORLD_ORDER">
			<Text>Adopting new Social Policies costs 10% less [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TIRELESS_WATCH_SHORT">
			<Text>Tireless Watch</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_TIRELESS_WATCH">
			<Text>Airship units get +2 [ICON_MOVES] Movement.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LABOR_CASTES_SHORT">
			<Text>Labor Castes</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_LABOR_CASTES">
			<Text>20% less [ICON_HAPPINESS_4] Unhappiness from [ICON_CITIZEN] Population.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_INVENTORS_GUILD_SHORT">
			<Text>Inventor's Guild</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_TRAIT_INVENTORS_GUILD">
			<Text>Earn Great Scientists 50% faster.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Technologies-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ANALOG_COMPUTATION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Difference Engine[ENDCOLOR] and the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Analytical Engine[ENDCOLOR] national wonder, which boost a city's [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and [ICON_RESEARCH] Science.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ANALOG_COMPUTATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"There will always be plenty of things to compute in the detailed affairs of millions of people doing complicated things."[NEWLINE] - Vannevar Bush[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_REPLACEABLE_PARTS_HELP">
			<Text>Gives access to [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Great War Infantry[ENDCOLOR], the most advanced infantry unit in the world.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_RAILROAD_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Land Ironclad[ENDCOLOR], the first landship unit.  Also allows Workers to build [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Railroads[ENDCOLOR] on map tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ANALYTICAL_ENGINE_HELP">
			<Text>Provides access to the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Analytical Engine[ENDCOLOR] national wonder, which greatly increases [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ANALYTICAL_ENGINE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The whole of arithmetic now appeared within the grasp of mechanism."[NEWLINE] - Charles Babbage[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ECONOMIC_IMPERIALISM_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Grand Mansion[ENDCOLOR] and its national wonder counterpart, the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Biltmore House[ENDCOLOR], both of which grant [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ECONOMIC_IMPERIALISM_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Avarice, the spur of industry."[NEWLINE] - David Hume[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_PROPULSION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Destróier[ENDCOLOR] and the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Flyer[ENDCOLOR], which is the first air unit.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_PROPULSION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"To invent an airplane is nothing. To build an airplane is something. But to fly... is everything."[NEWLINE] - Ferdinand Ferber[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ERUPTIVES_HELP">
			<Text>Reveals [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric and allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Battleship[ENDCOLOR].</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ERUPTIVES_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Nature, to be commanded, must be obeyed."[NEWLINE] - Francis Bacon[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_EXPEDITIONARY_SCIENCE_HELP">
			<Text>Reveals [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium and allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Submarine[ENDCOLOR].  Also allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Trade College[ENDCOLOR], which increases a city's [ICON_RESEARCH] Science and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_EXPEDITIONARY_SCIENCE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"In wilderness I sense the miracle of life, and behind it our scientific accomplishments fade to trivia."[NEWLINE] - Charles Lindbergh[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_VERTICAL_INTEGRATION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Stock Exchange[ENDCOLOR], which increases [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_VERTICAL_INTEGRATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Competition is a sin."[NEWLINE] - John D. Rockefeller[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_LANDSHIPS_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Landship[ENDCOLOR], a powerful land unit.  Also grants access to the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Patent Office[ENDCOLOR], which increases a city's [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_LANDSHIPS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The defenders had been driven right and left as soon as the prow of this land ironclad had loomed up over the front of the trench."[NEWLINE] - H.G. Wells[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_NOBLESSE_OBLIGE_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Stadium[ENDCOLOR], which increases your empire's [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_NOBLESSE_OBLIGE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Virtue is the truest nobility."[NEWLINE] - Miguel de Cervantes[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_AIRSHIPS_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Airship[ENDCOLOR], which can travel over land and sea alike.  Also allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Inventor's Hall[ENDCOLOR] national wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_INFERNAL_COMBUSTION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Luboric Refinery[ENDCOLOR], which will produce [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric resources for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_INFERNAL_COMBUSTION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"The most tangible of all visible mysteries - fire."[NEWLINE] - James Henry Leigh Hunt[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_GOSPEL_OF_WEALTH_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Philanthroporium[ENDCOLOR], which increases a city's [ICON_CULTURE] Culture and [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_GOSPEL_OF_WEALTH_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I resolved to stop accumulating and begin the infinitely more serious and difficult task of wise distribution."[NEWLINE] - Andrew Carnegie[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_AUTOMATA_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Aetherium Fabricator[ENDCOLOR], which will produce [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium resources for you.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_AUTOMATA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Civilization advances by extending the number of important operations which we can perform without thinking about them."[NEWLINE] - Alfred North Whitehead[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_URANOGRAPHY_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Airship Hangar[ENDCOLOR], which gives extra Experience to trained units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_URANOGRAPHY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"I fly because it releases my mind from the tyranny of petty things."[NEWLINE] - Antoine de Saint Exupéry[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_GALVANOMAGNETISM_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Tesla Coil[ENDCOLOR], which greatly increases a city's [ICON_RESEARCH] Science output and slightly boosts [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_CIVIL_DEFENSE_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Anti-Aircraft Gun[ENDCOLOR], a powerful counter to air units, and the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Military Base[ENDCOLOR], which increases a city's defense.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_CIVIL_DEFENSE_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Defense is superior to opulence."[NEWLINE] - Adam Smith[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_LAND_LEVIATHAN_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the most powerful landship unit, the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Land Leviathan[ENDCOLOR].</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_LAND_LEVIATHAN_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Speak softly and carry a big stick; you will go far."[NEWLINE] - Theodore Roosevelt[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_RADIO_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Torre de Difusão[ENDCOLOR], a building which greatly increases the [ICON_CULTURE] Cultural output of a city.  Also grants access to the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Carnegie Hall[ENDCOLOR] national wonder, another large source of [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_ROBOTICS_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Automated Factory[ENDCOLOR], which significantly increases the [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production output of a city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_SKY_FORTRESS_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the most powerful airship unit, the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Sky Fortress[ENDCOLOR].</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_SKY_FORTRESS_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Any sufficiently advanced technology is indistinguishable from magic."[NEWLINE] - Arthur C. Clarke[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_PERPETUAL_MOTION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Perpetual Motion Engine[ENDCOLOR] national wonder, which provides an enormous boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_PERPETUAL_MOTION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Give me a place to stand and a lever long enough, and I shall move the world."[NEWLINE] - Archimedes[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_SUBTERRANEAN_EXPLORATION_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Subterranean Outpost[ENDCOLOR] and its national wonder counterpart the [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]Subterranean Colony[ENDCOLOR], both of which provide a powerful boost to a city's [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_SUBTERRANEAN_EXPLORATION_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"One just principle from the depths of a cave is more powerful than an army."[NEWLINE] - José Martí[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_TECHNOCRACY_HELP">
			<Text>Allows you to build the late-game [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]CN Tower[ENDCOLOR] wonder, which provides uma Torre de Difusão in all of your cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_TECHNOCRACY_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"A government of reason is better than one of force."[NEWLINE] - Thomas Jefferson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_THE_GRAND_IDEA_HELP">
			<Text>May be researched more than once.  Provides [ICON_CULTURE] Culture each time it is successfully researched.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TECH_THE_GRAND_IDEA_QUOTE">
			<Text>[NEWLINE][TAB][TAB]"Men love to wonder, and that is the seed of our science."[NEWLINE] - Ralph Waldo Emerson[NEWLINE][TAB]</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Resources -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_RESOURCE_ALUMINUM_HELP">
			<Text>Used by airship Units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_RESOURCE_ALUMINUM_TEXT">
			<Text>Aetherium was first discovered by expedition parties who mistook it for silver.  As their mining operations expanded, the flakes and chunks of it were gathered into large parcels for shipment, and something very strange happened.  The parcels began to levitate off the ground.  Scientists began to analyze this material's unusual properties.  When masses of it are gathered together, it has the power to counteract gravity.  With careful engineering, these counter-gravitational forces can be guided into a reliable source of lift, allowing ships to float in the sky.  Its importance in the affairs of empire continues to grow, yet even today its properties are not well understood.  One careless inventor's apparatus electrified a small chunk of aetherium, causing it to shoot upwards and punch a hole through the roof.  The sample, engraved with the inventor's marking for experimental verification, was found weeks later, miles away from where it launched.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_RESOURCE_URANIUM_HELP">
			<Text>Used by landship Units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_RESOURCE_URANIUM_TEXT">
			<Text>Appearing in the natural world as a nondescript, dull green ore, luboric glows under high temperatures.  It is much more powerful and volatile than its predecessor, coal, and acts as the ultimate energy source for factories and vehicles alike. The chain of reactions and mechanisms required to utilize luboric  are complex and unprecedented in the science of energies.  Whereas most fuel sources yield their energy when burned, luboric is unfazed by flame, its green glow the only apparent reaction.  To unlock the enormous potential present within chunks of luboric ore, it must be submerged in a solution of enzymes and subjected to both heat and pressure.  The key reaction is not combustion, but dissolution.  Its toxic gaseous exhaust must be carefully guided; if the fumes get trapped in a valve or corner for more than a few seconds it will eat through metal. Only with precautions will its legendary energy be loosed from its chemical bonds.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Promotions-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MOVE_ALL_TERRAIN">
			<Text>Move All Terrain</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_MOVE_ALL_TERRAIN_HELP">
			<Text>As an airship, this unit may move over both land and sea tiles.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_ANTI_AIR">
			<Text>Bonus vs fighters and airships (150)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_PEDIA_PROMOTION_ANTI_AIR">
			<Text>Bonus vs fighters and airships (150)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_ANTI_AIR_II">
			<Text>Bonus vs airships (150)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_PROMOTION_ANTI_TANK">
			<Text>Bonus vs landships (100)</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_PEDIA_PROMOTION_ANTI_TANK">
			<Text>Bonus vs landships (100)</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Units-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNITCOMBAT_HELICOPTER">
			<Text>Airship Units</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNIT_GREAT_WAR_INFANTRY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Great War Infantry is the strongest infantry unit in the game.  It can capture cities, but struggles when going up against landship and airship units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_GREAT_WAR_INFANTRY">
			<Text>Strongest infantry unit in the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_BATTLESHIP">
			<Text>Most powerful ranged Naval unit in the game.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNIT_SUBMARINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Submarine is a specialized ship-killing vessel. It is invisible to most units - except for Destróiers and other Submarines - until it attacks, or is adjacent to another unit. The Submarine can enter ice hexes. Use the Submarine to patrol enemy waters and sink enemy ships, and to guard your own ships against attacks from enemy subs. </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_SUBMARINE">
			<Text>Invisible to all Units except Destróiers and other Submarines. Can cause major damage to other ships if they get into range without being seen.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_UNIT_HELP_ANTI_AIRCRAFT_GUN">
			<Text>Will intercept enemy Flyers which try to attack nearby Units.  Also effective against airships.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LAND_IRONCLAD_TEXT">
			<Text>Much had been learned from the construction of the "Iron Horse" that was the railroad.  Soon, inventors tried to engineer a vehicle with the power of a locomotive without need of a track.  Designing the apparatus for moving the unwieldy metal beasts that were the first prototypes proved extremely difficult.  The process merged into a simpler design with much less armor plating, but enough to withstand gunfire and the elements.  The first drivers found that having a light, maneuverable craft was much more effective than a bulky one.  It allowed for quick travel on less fuel, as well as agility in combat.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LAND_IRONCLAD_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The most basic type of landship unit, the Land Ironclad is well armored and shines in ground combat.  Use it to easily defeat primitive land units and wear down cities for capture.  Its armor will somewhat protect it against the smaller guns of Flyers, but it is very vulnerable to cannon fire from Airships.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LAND_IRONCLAD_HELP">
			<Text>First landship unit.  Strong against other land units, but weak against airships.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LANDSHIP_TEXT">
			<Text>The Landship was everything the land ironclad was to be but was not.  The discovery of luboric increased the energy available to power such a vehicle exponentially, allowing for more armor and weaponry while maintaining the same maneuverability.  It became the gold standard on the battlefield, capable of destroying nearly any other land unit.  With several of them, a commander could quickly take out an army or encircle a city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LANDSHIP_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Landship is heavily armored and excels at ground combat.  Use it to defeat other land units and wear down cities for capture.  Its armor will help protect it against the smaller guns of Flyers, but it is vulnerable to cannon fire from Airships.  Escort the Landship with units that are strong against air units, such as Flyers and Anti-Air Guns, for maximum survivability.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LANDSHIP_HELP">
			<Text>More powerful version of the Land Ironclad.  Strong against other land units, but weak against airships.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LAND_LEVIATHAN_TEXT">
			<Text>The Land Leviathan is the pinnacle of ground combat.  Taking its name from the fantastic sea monster, it boasts immense firepower.  It can fire from almost any angle and trek across the land at great speeds.  It is outfitted with a crew of sixteen: some man the cannons, others tend the luboric engine, and a pair act as pilot and navigator.  During training they learn to move and think as one unit, developing a shorthand language for giving complex commands quickly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LAND_LEVIATHAN_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Land Leviathan is the pinnacle of landship units, bringing devastation to any other land unit.  Use it to destroy vulnerable enemy Anti-Air Guns and ensure your air units stay safe.  Its armor will help protect it against the smaller guns of Flyers, but it is still vulnerable to cannon fire from Airships and Sky Fortresses.  It is best to protect the expensive Land Leviathan with units that are strong against air units, such as Flyers and Anti-Air Guns.  </Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LAND_LEVIATHAN_HELP">
			<Text>Most advanced landship unit.  Strong against other land units, but weak against airships.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLYER_TEXT">
			<Text>The Flyer began as an inventor's novelty, one of the many results of the widespread participation in science brought on by the Age of Steam.  Advancements in propulsion had done wonders for land and sea vehicles; why not apply them in the pursuit of the eternal dream of human flight?  The engine mounted on the fuselage was bulky, so every ounce of weight had to be saved if the plane was to fly.  Cloth was used instead of metal wherever possible.  Later, as technology advanced, weapons were mounted on it and liberties were taken with the original design.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLYER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Flyers have a short range and a moderate attack.  They excel at hit and run tactics, especially against Airships and Sky Fortresses, which are too bulky to effectively dodge their strikes.  Their limited range restricts them to mostly defensive roles at first, but later on the Sky Fortress can act as their mobile base, transporting them directly into the battlefield.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_FLYER_HELP">
			<Text>Excellent against airships, but not very strong against land units.  It also has a limited range, and must base at a city or Sky Fortress.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_AIRSHIP_TEXT">
			<Text>Until the discovery of aetherium, it was believed that only light and maneuverable craft - such as the Flyer - would ever travel the skies.  The airship is a strange yet majestic contraption.  With the new material, the original engineers and inventors of the airship were free to put nearly anything in the air, going against the constraints of the science which had been the guiding laws of their professions heretofore.  Necessarily, the product reflected something familiar from past history: a seafaring vessel.  It had a deck, armaments on either side, and a balloon in place of a sail.  Early airship crews adopted naval conventions of rank and hierarchy.  Soon, though, the reality of sustained flight took on its own character.  Ship designs became more and more experimental.  Airship pilots and crew developed their own culture, at once genteel and whimsical.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_AIRSHIP_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Airship is able to move over land and sea, shortening the distance needed to travel to the battlefield and opening up chances to strike enemies from a direction they do not expect.  Its large cannons can attack enemy Airships nearby or rain destruction down on targets below.  Flyers and Anti-Air Guns pose a threat, so take them out early or bring other unit types for support.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_AIRSHIP_HELP">
			<Text>First airship unit, able to move over land and sea.  Powerful against land targets, but vulnerable to Flyers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SKY_FORTRESS_TEXT">
			<Text>The majestic Sky Fortress is quite a sight to behold.  Much larger than the airship, it casts a wide shadow on the ground below that strikes fear into the hearts of foes.  It is outfitted with heavy weaponry, but kept aloft through advanced applications of aetherium's lift properties.  Inside the ship's body are a variety of accommodations: war rooms used by generals above the battlefield, a small hangar which can host a squadron of Flyers, and even parlors for recreation.  The Sky Fortress became the centerpiece of airship fleets, a mobile command center that could rain death on the land below and blow enemy airships out of the sky.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SKY_FORTRESS_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Sky Fortress is the most advanced type of airship unit, and houses significant firepower.  Not only can it use its cannons to attack land targets and other airships, but also it can act as a mobile base for a Flyer.  With a Flyer running strikes on nearby airship units, the Sky Fortress poses a serious threat to many types of units, but is still vulnerable to enemy Flyers and Anti-Air Guns.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_SKY_FORTRESS_HELP">
			<Text>Most advanced airship unit.  May act as base for a Flyer.  Powerful attacks, but vulnerable to Flyers.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Unique Buildings-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_GRANDSTAND_TEXT">
			<Text>The people of Dalmace understand the importance of public spaces to their livelihood and advancement.  The Grandstand acts as a venue for entertainment and culture alike, attracting crowds from far away.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRANDSTAND_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Grandstand can only be built by Alderdice, and replaces the Stadium.  Unlike the Stadium, it provides [ICON_CULTURE] Culture, helping to expand territory and gain new Social Policies more quickly.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRANDSTAND_HELP">
			<Text>Can only be built by Alderdice.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_LUBORIC_FACTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>The value of luboric in creating engines for landships was clear to all of the empires, but the industrial masterminds of Orlin saw its potential to improve production.  They created factories specifically for luboric, which could refine trace amounts into usable quantities and use them for the efficient production of goods.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LUBORIC_FACTORY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Luboric Factory can only be built by Curnow.  Unlike the Luboric Refinery, which it replaces, the Luboric Factory gives a bonus to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production which increases with the number of [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric resources worked by the city it is built in.  This bonus stacks with Curnow's trait.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LUBORIC_FACTORY_HELP">
			<Text>Can only be built by Curnow.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Provides [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2 [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric[ENDCOLOR] resources.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Each source of [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric worked by this city provides +1 [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_TORUS_DYNAMO_TEXT">
			<Text>The scientists of Vedria were mesmerized by galvanomagnetic forces, and built entire research laboratories dedicated to it.  At the center of these laboratories was the Torus Dynamo, which crackled with electric current.  It served as both the subject of research and the energy source that powered research.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TORUS_DYNAMO_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Torus Dynamo can only be built by Griggs.  It provides a boost to a city's [ICON_RESEARCH] Science greater than the Tesla Coil, which it replaces.  This bonus can be very helpful for picking up older technologies you may have missed, or when working towards expensive Future Era technologies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TORUS_DYNAMO_HELP">
			<Text>Can only be built by Griggs.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_AETHERIUM_FACTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>Aetherium is a substance that seems to defy the laws of the natural world, and its uses are many.  Agents of Pulias made this resource the focus of much of their efforts.  The Aetherium Factory is able to maximize the effects of even small amounts of aetherium, which can then be used by traders to bedazzle commoners out of their cash or craft highly valued commercial novelties.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AETHERIUM_FACTORY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Aetherium Factory can only be built by Cutler.  Unlike the Aetherium Fabricator, which it replaces, the Aetherium Factory gives a bonus to [ICON_GOLD] Gold which increases with the number of [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium resources worked by the city it is built in.  This bonus stacks with Cutler's trait.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AETHERIUM_FACTORY_HELP">
			<Text>Can only be built by Cutler.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Provides [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2 [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium[ENDCOLOR] resources.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Each source of [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium worked by this city provides +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_AERODROME_TEXT">
			<Text>The famed Aerodromes of Eruch doubled as a place of airship manufacture and training.  Crewmen participated directly in the process of construction, which not only acted as training but also improved efficiency.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AERODROME_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Aerodrome can only be built by Rotheram.  It replaces the Airship Hangar, providing a bonus to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when building air units: Flyers, Airships, and Sky Fortresses.  Like the Airship Hangar, it also provides extra Experience to trained air units.  Use the Aerodrome to build an experienced air fleet in a short time.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AERODROME_HELP">
			<Text>Can only be built by Rotheram.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+15 XP for air Units.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]+10% [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production when building air units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Buildings-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_DIFFERENCE_ENGINE_TEXT">
			<Text>The first difference engines were small, expensive tools restricted to performing complex calculations for businesses or laboratories.  Once the value of computational logic was recognized, however, larger and larger models were built.  Now their use extends from the smallest financial transaction to statistical analysis for affairs of state.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIFFERENCE_ENGINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and [ICON_RESEARCH] Science.  Build one in each city to unlock the Analytical Engine national wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_DIFFERENCE_ENGINE_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocks the Analytical Engine when built in every city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_GRAND_MANSION_TEXT">
			<Text>The operations of empire brought many opportunities for prosperity through trade, invention, and industry.  There were many newcomers to the ranks of nobility, and they used their fortunes to construct decadent, grand mansions which became the gathering places of high culture and business.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_MANSION_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a boost to [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.  Build one in each city to unlock the Biltmore House national wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_GRAND_MANSION_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocks Biltmore House when built in every city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_TRADE_COLLEGE_TEXT">
			<Text>As the possibilities of science continued to expand in scope, empires recognized the value of subsidizing the education of young scientists, inventors, explorers, and entrepreneurs.  Advantages in these - big and small alike - were sought after; anything could be the edge that would outclass rival empires.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRADE_COLLEGE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a large boost to [ICON_RESEARCH] Science as well as some [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TRADE_COLLEGE_HELP">
			<Text>Provides [ICON_RESEARCH] Science and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_PATENT_OFFICE_TEXT">
			<Text>In the age of miraculous science, inventors fill the streets, trying to peddle their wares.  Their brilliance is hidden in a sea of competition and empty promise.  Patents streamline the process of invention, weeding out the spurious and rewarding ingenuity.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PATENT_OFFICE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a boost to [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production, as well as a slot for a Scientist specialist.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PATENT_OFFICE_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocks Inventor's Hall when built in every city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_LUBORIC_REFINERY_TEXT">
			<Text>Valuable luboric deposits are a rare find, but once its chemical composition was known, scientists were able to find trace amounts nearly anywhere.  Through elaborate chemical processes, these trace amounts can be refined into potent compounds that mimic the effects of pure luboric.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LUBORIC_REFINERY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric resources without needing to own a tile with the resource.  With these resources, you can train more landship units for your army.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LUBORIC_REFINERY_HELP">
			<Text>Provides [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2 [ICON_RES_URANIUM] Luboric[ENDCOLOR] resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_PHILANTHROPORIUM_TEXT">
			<Text>A cross between philanthropy and the great trade emporiums in this age of international trade, the philanthroporium offers premium charity to the common man at a fraction of the price.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PHILANTHROPORIUM_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a large boost to [ICON_CULTURE] Culture as well as some [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.  Build one in each city to unlock the Carnegie Hall national wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PHILANTHROPORIUM_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocks Carnegie Hall when built in every city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_TESLA_COIL_TEXT">
			<Text>Electricity was initially a wild and poorly-understood force.  Its power was difficult to control, which is why the Tesla Coil was designed.  It soon became indispensable for scientific inquiry.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TESLA_COIL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a large boost to [ICON_RESEARCH] Science as well as some [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_TESLA_COIL_HELP">
			<Text>Provides [ICON_RESEARCH] Science and [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_AETHERIUM_FABRICATOR_TEXT">
			<Text>As the mysteries of aetherium continue to be probed, scientists have found ways to make smaller quantities of the resource just as effective as a large quantity, and even craft synthetic versions that approximate its effects.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AETHERIUM_FABRICATOR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium resources without needing to own a tile with the resource.  With these resources, you can train more airship units for your army.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AETHERIUM_FABRICATOR_HELP">
			<Text>Provides [COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]2 [ICON_RES_ALUMINUM] Aetherium[ENDCOLOR] resources.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_AIRSHIP_HANGAR_TEXT">
			<Text>Flyers and airships can land anywhere there is a flat stretch of land, but having a dedicated space to act as base of operations significantly increases both morale and potential for training new crew members.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AIRSHIP_HANGAR_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides extra Experience to trained air units: Flyers, Airships, and Sky Fortresses.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AIRSHIP_HANGAR_HELP">
			<Text>+15 XP for air Units.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_AUTOMATED_FACTORY_TEXT">
			<Text>The toil of the common man can be traced to the hours he spends slaving in factories under the worst conditions.  By applying knowledge of automated machines, not only can his plight be improved, but efficiency can be increased.  Machines have no need of sleep.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUTOMATED_FACTORY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a large boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production as well as some [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness. Build one in each city to unlock the Perpetual Motion Engine national wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_AUTOMATED_FACTORY_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocks Perpetual Motion Engine when built in every city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_SUBTERRANEAN_OUTPOST_TEXT">
			<Text>The sheer vehicular power of the steam era was used to easily traverse the land and even the sky, but it was not for several decades that intrepid scientists thought to probe the depths of the earth.  With proper living quarters and equipment, a subterranean outpost can prove to be a valuable source of raw materials.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUBTERRANEAN_OUTPOST_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Provides a large boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production as well as some [ICON_RESEARCH] Science. Build one in each city to unlock the Subterranean Colony national wonder.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUBTERRANEAN_OUTPOST_HELP">
			<Text>Unlocks Subterranean Colony when built in every city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_BUILDING_POLICE_STATION_HELP">
			<Text>Reduces enemy spy stealing rate by 25%.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_BUILDING_POLICE_STATION_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Police stations slow down the rate at which enemy spies can steal technologies from your city.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- National Wonders -->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_ANALYTICAL_ENGINE_TEXT">
			<Text>Towering above a mere Difference Engine, the Analytical Engine acts as the logistical brain of an empire.  It is tended by a staff of specialists, and its valuable operation time is carefully budgeted.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ANALYTICAL_ENGINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Analytical Engine may only be built once each of your cities has a Difference Engine, and you may only build one in your empire.  It provides a large boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_ANALYTICAL_ENGINE_HELP">
			<Text>É preciso ter construído a Difference Engine in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_BILTMORE_HOUSE_TEXT">
			<Text>The Biltmore House is a center of refinement and commerce.  Its every room is manicured to entertain guests and facilitate important business transactions in the smoothest and most comfortable manner.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BILTMORE_HOUSE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Biltmore House may only be built once each of your cities has a Grand Mansion, and you may only build one in your empire.  It provides a boost to [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_BILTMORE_HOUSE_HELP">
			<Text>É preciso ter construído a Grand Mansion in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_INVENTORS_HALL_TEXT">
			<Text>A veritable madhouse of innovation, the Inventor's Hall is a public forum of discovery where inventors can meet and use provided tools to devise profitable gadgets which push the boundaries of science.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INVENTORS_HALL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Inventor's Hall may only be built once each of your cities has a Patent Office, and you may only build one in your empire.  It provides a boost to [ICON_GOLD] Gold and [ICON_RESEARCH] Science.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_INVENTORS_HALL_HELP">
			<Text>É preciso ter construído a Patent Office in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_CARNEGIE_HALL_TEXT">
			<Text>Serving high and low culture alike, Carnegie Hall is a grand venue which attracts the most talented of artists to perform and share their ideals on a national stage.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CARNEGIE_HALL_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Carnegie Hall may only be built once each of your cities has a Philanthroporium, and you may only build one in your empire.  It provides a large boost to [ICON_CULTURE] Culture as well as a small boost to [ICON_HAPPINESS_1] Happiness.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_CARNEGIE_HALL_HELP">
			<Text>É preciso ter construído a Philanthroporium in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_SUBTERRANEAN_COLONY_TEXT">
			<Text>Once outposts had been established in the depths of the earth, empires recruited civilians for colonization.  With technological advancements and reliable supply lines, a small city could be maintained beneath the earth.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUBTERRANEAN_COLONY_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Subterranean Colony may only be built once each of your cities has a Subterranean Outpost, and you may only build one in your empire.  It provides a large boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production and [ICON_CULTURE] Culture.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_SUBTERRANEAN_COLONY_HELP">
			<Text>É preciso ter construído a Subterranean Outpost in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_CIV5_BUILDINGS_PERPETUAL_MOTION_ENGINE_TEXT">
			<Text>Scientists tried to unlock the secret of perpetual motion for centuries.  With advances in robotics and galvanomagnetic forces, it finally became possible.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PERPETUAL_MOTION_ENGINE_STRATEGY">
			<Text>The Perpetual Motion Engine may only be built once each of your cities has an Automated Factory, and you may only build one in your empire.  It provides an enormous boost to [ICON_PRODUCTION] Production as well as a moderate bonus to [ICON_GOLD] Gold.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_PERPETUAL_MOTION_ENGINE_HELP">
			<Text>É preciso ter construído an Automated Factory in all cities.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Leader Dialog-->
		<!-- Luther Griggs (Gustavus Adolphus)-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>I say, it is a pleasure to meet you! I am Luther Griggs, inventor extraordinaire, leader of Vedria! Let us share our knowledge in the spirit of science and friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>The music of our machines is upon your doorstep. I'll be sure to preserve what I can of your cities so that I may learn from your methods.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DECLAREWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_CATHERINE_DECLAREWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>Well met, sir. I hope that you continue the pursuit of knowledge and invention in my absence.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DEFEATED_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_DEFEATED_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_WARBLUFF_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_WARBLUFF_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXANDER_WINWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_WINWAR_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WUZETIAN_WINWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_LOSEWAR_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_LOSEWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRIBUTE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXANDER_TRIBUTE_NO_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_4}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_TRADE_NO_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_ATTACKED_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXANDER_ATTACKED_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_ATTACKED_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXANDER_ATTACKED_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_GUSTAVUS_ADOLPHUS_ATTACKED_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ALEXANDER_ATTACKED_3}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Cyrus Rotheram (Bismarck)-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Ah, salutations. Allow me to introduce myself. I am Cyrus Rotheram of Eruch, known for our great military might. I hope you to be a valuable ally, or I shall judge you a worthy foe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_FIRSTGREETING_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>I shall relish this game of war with you, and then our airships will cast your land into shadow.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DECLAREWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I bow to you, sir, as you have proved to be my match. Enjoy your victory.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DEFEATED_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_MONTEZUMA_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_LOSEWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BISMARCK_LOSEWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_QUOTE_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_QUOTE_4">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BISMARCK_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_4}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ASKIA_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ASKIA_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TRIBUTE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_TRIBUTE_NO_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ASKIA_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ASKIA_WINWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_BISMARCK_WINWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BISMARCK_WINWAR_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Ignace Curnow (Catherine)-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Behold the greatest cog in the industrial machine, the nation of Orlin! I am Ignace Curnow, and shall warn you, sir, that any foolery shall be dealt with severely.  My time is of great value.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>Our factories have long prepared for this moment. You stand no chance against the progress of industry!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_DECLAREWAR_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>You, sir, are a villain. Go ahead, take our factories, but the world shall never know the greatness of industry in your hands.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_DEFEATED_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_ATTACKED_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_CATHERINE_ATTACKED_3}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_ATTACKED_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_CATHERINE_ATTACKED_4}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_LOSEWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_SULEIMAN_LOSEWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_LOSEWAR_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_MARIA_LOSEWAR_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_LOSEWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_LOSEWAR_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_QUOTE_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRADE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRADE_NO_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRADE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_SELASSIE_TRADE_NO_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRADE_YES_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRADE_YES_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRADE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRADE_YES_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRADE_YES_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRADE_YES_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_SULEIMAN_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRIBUTE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRIBUTE_NO_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_TRIBUTE_YES_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRIBUTE_YES_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_CATHERINE_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_SULEIMAN_WINWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Octavius Cutler (Elizabeth)-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Come, my good man, and let us talk a while. My name is Octavius Cutler of Pulias, perhaps you have heard of me? No matter. Pray tell me about yourself and your great accomplishments.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_4">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_FIRSTGREETING_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>This will be quick, I assure you. Be at peace in the knowledge that your defeat will help Pulias grow stronger.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DECLAREWAR_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DECLAREWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEFEATED_1">
			<Text>I bow to you, sir, for your strong victory. My nation may have risen quietly, but the world knows that we did not go down in the same fashion.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEFEATED_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WUZETIAN_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_3}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_4}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_TRADE_NO_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_TRADE_NO_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_DARIUS_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADE_YES_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_DARIUS_TRADE_YES_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADEREQUEST_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HARUN_TRADEREQUEST_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRADEREQUEST_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIAWATHA_TRADEREQUEST_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIAWATHA_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_YES_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_TRIBUTE_YES_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIAWATHA_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_ELIZABETH_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_DARIUS_WINWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Clinton Alderdice (Napoleon)-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Splendid meeting you, sir, simply splendid! Welcome to humble Dalmace. My name is Clinton Alderdice, and I happily offer you my hand in friendship.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_FIRSTGREETING_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_FIRSTGREETING_4">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_FIRSTGREETING_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DECLAREWAR_1">
			<Text>My dear fellow, I must apologize for this act of aggression. Unfortunately there is no alternative.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DECLAREWAR_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DECLAREWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DEFEATED_2">
			<Text>Good gracious, this injustice is uncalled for! Dalmace may be gone in name, but it will live on through the common man.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DEFEATED_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DEFEATED_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_DEMANDTRIBUTE_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIAWATHA_DEMANDTRIBUTE_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_LOSEWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIAWATHA_LOSEWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_QUOTE_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_QUOTE_2">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_QUOTE_3">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_QUOTE_4">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TEXT_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NEEDMORE_ANGRY_2}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NEEDMORE_HAPPY_3}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NEEDMORE_NEUTRAL_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NEEDMORE_NEUTRAL_3}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ODA_TRADE_NO_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WILLIAM_TRADE_NO_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_ODA_TRADE_YES_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_TRADEREQUEST_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_WASHINGTON_TRIBUTE_NO_ANGRY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRIBUTE_NO_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HIAWATHA_TRIBUTE_NO_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_RAMKHAMHAENG_TRIBUTE_YES_HAPPY}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_TRIBUTE_YES_NEUTRAL">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_BOUDICCA_TRIBUTE_YES_NEUTRAL}</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_NAPOLEON_WINWAR_1">
			<Text>{TXT_KEY_LEADER_HARUN_WINWAR_1}</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Generic-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_FIRSTGREETING_1">
			<Text>Greetings, good sir! You appear to be an honourable gentleman. May our dealings long be amicable, and if we should meet on the battlefield may the best man win.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_FIRSTGREETING_2">
			<Text>Ho, sir! I beg that you will state your business. Undoubtedly, your intentions are most admirable, else I shall warn you that I am quite a formidable foe.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_POSITIVE_1">
			<Text>Very good.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_POSITIVE_2">
			<Text>Just so.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_POSITIVE_3">
			<Text>Quite right.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_POSITIVE_4">
			<Text>Precisely so.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_POSITIVE_5">
			<Text>Most admirable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_POSITIVE_6">
			<Text>This arrangement is most agreeable.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_NEGATIVE_1">
			<Text>I should think not.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_NEGATIVE_2">
			<Text>This is an outrage!</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_LEADER_MISC_NEGATIVE_3">
			<Text>You offend me, sir.</Text>
		</Row>
		<!-- Backups for Policies and Traits-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_POLICY_UNITED_FRONT">
			<Text>United Front</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_POLICY_UNITED_FRONT_HELP">
			<Text>[COLOR_POSITIVE_TEXT]United Front[ENDCOLOR][NEWLINE]+10% [ICON_PRODUCTION] when building Wonders and new Cities start with an extra 1 [ICON_CITIZEN] Population.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TRAIT_INTELLIGENCE_NETWORK_SHORT">
			<Text>Intelligence Network</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_STEAMPUNK_SCENARIO_TRAIT_INTELLIGENCE_NETWORK">
			<Text>Receieve 2 extra Spies.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_pt_BR>
</GameData>
